<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PW-1 | My Notes</title><link>https://blog.kbx.codes/pw-1/</link><atom:link href="https://blog.kbx.codes/pw-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>PW-1</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://blog.kbx.codes/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>PW-1</title><link>https://blog.kbx.codes/pw-1/</link></image><item><title>Teenage Engineering and it's flaws</title><link>https://blog.kbx.codes/pw-1/teenage-engineering-and-its-flaws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kbx.codes/pw-1/teenage-engineering-and-its-flaws/</guid><description>&lt;p>The OP-1 is a amazing piece of gear with a great build and gives an almost &amp;ldquo;toy&amp;rdquo; like feel to music making. However it&amp;rsquo;s limitations and price are an incredible setback to it reaching higher audiences, among other things. What can we do to remedy this?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="some-background">Some Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Founded in 2005, Teenage Engineering would work hard on their product, the OP-1, which would release 5 years later in 2010. Teenage Engineering&amp;rsquo;s target audience around this time was for young musicians and indie artists. This however, makes absolutely no sense, when you look at the price tag. The OP-1 costs &lt;em>&lt;strong>$1000&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>! The synth doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have expandable storage, you are stuck with 256mb for storing everything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For one, who would shelve &lt;em>that&lt;/em> much money into such small gear? You could get a high spec PC, a DAW and a synth with that money, it&amp;rsquo;s very perplexing on Teenage Engineering part.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The story doesn&amp;rsquo;t get better either. Recently, Teenage Engineering announced the OP-1 Field, which was essentially an upgraded OP-1 that costs &lt;em>&lt;strong>$2000????&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>. They claim to have made &amp;ldquo;100 upgrades&amp;rdquo;, but this almost feels like an excuse, because looking at these changes, it&amp;rsquo;s mostly software related things. So why did they not push out an update instead of release this?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One word.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I and many other people do not know who Teenage Engineering&amp;rsquo;s target audience is anymore. It seems as if they want to appease rich musicians (and rich folk in general) with having this machine that they would use once and most likely use it as some sort of fashion accessory. I like to think of them as the Apple of synths. Sure they make great products, but that comes at the cost of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Lack of user expandability&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Unrealistic high prices&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="now-what">Now what?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I thought it would be a fun project to try and make my own. An OP-1 alternative that&amp;rsquo;s actually cheap and good. The synths and whatnot, I can program easily, hardware wise, I&amp;rsquo;m not so good. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll stick to a Raspberry Pi and try making something around it.
Over the next few months I will be prototyping and posting here for updates on the whole project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks for reading.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>